simplepractice.com 2018-08-22

# Secure Practice Management Software | SimplePractice Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to the SimplePractice, LLC (“SimplePractice” or “We” or “Us”) websites located at [https://simplepractice.com](https://simplepractice.com/), [www.simplepractice.ca](https://www.simplepractice.ca/), and [https://secure.simplepractice.com ](https://secure.simplepractice.com/) (and any affiliated sub-domain and mobile applications (“Mobile Apps”) and sites, collectively “Website”) and the services offered on the Website. This privacy policy describes how SimplePractice collects and uses the personal information you provide on the Website. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which you have engaged SimplePractice. This privacy policy also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. This privacy policy agreement does not pertain to protected health information (“PHI”) entered by registered users (“Users”). Our Terms of Service agreement, found at <https://www.simplepractice.com/terms>, defines the privacy of patient information for registered members of our practice management services (“Members”).

### 1\. Member Controlled Data

SimplePractice has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes on behalf of Members. An individual who seeks access to their data, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his or her inquiry to the Member, who controls such data. If an individual requests that the Member remove the individual’s data, it is the Member’s responsibility to respond to such requests.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Members for as long as needed to provide services to our Members. We will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### 2\. Information Collection and Use

We collect the following information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Financial Information such as credit card number, and Tax ID
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name and password

We also collect the following information from you:

  * Information about your business such as company name and license number

We use this information to

  * Fulfill your order
  * Send you an order confirmation
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send product updates
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter and marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our Web site and marketing efforts

We do not ask you for, access, or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or services.

### 3\. Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

#### Service Providers

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as an email service provider to send emails on our behalf or for payment processing. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services for us. 

#### Legal Disclaimer

We may also disclose your personal information: 

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * if SimplePractice is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, SimplePractice may sell or transfer user information (including personal information) as part of any such transaction; or
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### 4\. User Access and Choice

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, or delete/remove it by logging into your SimplePractice account and making the changes in your account settings. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

#### Opt-out Preferences

Receiving emails from our site is part of our service. When you sign up for a SimplePractice account, we will use your name and email address to communicate with you about your account, including account information, account alerts, and product education.

We may also use your name and email address to send you marketing emails, including newsletters and promotions from SimplePractice and/or from our partners. If you no longer wish to receive these marketing emails, you may opt out of them by using the unsubscribe link contained in the email.

### 5\. Tracking Technologies / Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site and within our platform.

We use session ID cookies to allow you to access your account and to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited. We do not honor Do Not Track requests. The information from use of these tracking technologies may be combined with information that is personally identifiable so that we can make our website more interesting to you.

For California Users: Please note that the Website is not presently configured to respond to DNT or “do not track” signals from web browsers or mobile devices.

#### Analytics / Log Files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files on our site and within our platform. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site and platform, to track users’ movements around the site and platform, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information that you have provided to us and/or with other information that is publicly available or that we receive from other reputable sources in order to make our Website and communications more targeted to your interests.

We may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Website, Members, and Users, and SimplePractice may utilize third parties to analyze the usage of the Website and Service.

####  3rd Party Tracking

Our third party partners may employ scripts that help them better manage content on our Web site and within our platform. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information that you have provided to us and/or with other information that is publicly available or that we receive from other reputable sources in order to make our Website and communications more targeted to your interests.

In addition, our business partners may use Cookies to provide us with anonymous data and information regarding the use of our Services. Specifically, some of our business partners use Cookies to show SimplePractice ads on other sites on the internet as a result of you using the Services. Such Cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. You may opt out of receiving Cookies placed by such third party vendors by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp").

Other Cookies used by our business partners may collect other non-personally identifying information, such as the computer’s IP address, type of operating system, type of internet browsing software, what web pages were viewed at what time, the geographic location of your internet service provider and demographic information, such as gender and age range. This information is used to provide us with more information about our users’ demographics and internet behaviors.

We may use your personally identifiable information to deliver the products and services that you request, enhance your experience on our Web site, and for internal business analysis, and other business purposes consistent with this policy.

### 6\. Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number and login credentials), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at security@simplepractice.com.

### 7\. Additional Information

#### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features on a third party site are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

#### Changes To This Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### Links To Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by SimplePractice. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

### 8\. Contact Us
